Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Dukungan Admin Tonton di kissasia.cam atau kisskh.org
[Milestone "Miles" Williams] Kiara, you are my star.
[Milestone "Miles" Williams] Kiara, kaulah bintangku.
[Dr. Kiara Guillory-Williams] Milestone, you are my moon.
[Dr. Kiara Guillory-Williams] Milestone, kaulah bulanku.
With this ring,
Dengan cincin ini,
you join the chain of my ancestors that goes back centuries.
Anda bergabung dengan rantai leluhur saya yang sudah ada sejak berabad-abad lalu.
[♪ seductive music playing]
[♪ musik menggoda dimainkan]
Thank you for being mine.
Terima kasih telah menjadi milikku.
Thank you for being you.
Terima kasih telah menjadi dirimu sendiri.
You fill me with love. You fill me with light.
Kau penuhi aku dengan cinta. Kau penuhi aku dengan cahaya.
[♪ seductive music continues]
[♪ musik menggoda berlanjut]
[record needle popping]
[suara jarum rekaman berbunyi]
[♪ sultry jazz music playing]
[♪ musik jazz yang sensual dimainkan]
[blows]
[meniup]
No, no, no, no. See, you play too much. You already know I gotta wake up early.
Tidak, tidak, tidak, tidak. Lihat, kamu terlalu banyak main. Kamu sudah tahu aku harus bangun pagi.
I gotta open up the gym in the morning.
Saya harus membuka pusat kebugaran di pagi hari.
[Kiara breathes deeply]
[Kiara menarik napas dalam-dalam]
[Kiara giggles]
[Kiara terkikik]
Tell me why you love this song again.
Ceritakan lagi mengapa Anda menyukai lagu ini.
'Cause the first time I heard it,
Karena pertama kali aku mendengarnya,
I was so struck by it,
Saya sangat terkesan dengan hal itu,
I immediately had to figure out who it was by,
Saya harus segera mencari tahu siapa orangnya,
so I could listen to it all the time.
Jadi saya bisa mendengarkannya sepanjang waktu.
Just like the first time I saw you.
Sama seperti pertama kali aku melihatmu.
I was so struck by you, I had to find out who you were,
Aku sangat terkesan padamu, aku harus mencari tahu siapa dirimu,
so I could find a way to get next to you every single day.
jadi aku bisa menemukan cara untuk berada di sampingmu setiap hari.
[Kiara chuckles]
[Kiara terkekeh]
Kinda creepy.
Agak menyeramkan.
[Miles laughs]
[Miles tertawa]
[laughing]
[tertawa]
[kiss smacks]
[ciuman menampar]
I think you're gonna like how this night ends.
Saya pikir Anda akan menyukai bagaimana malam ini berakhir.
[♪ music stops abruptly]
[♪ musik berhenti tiba-tiba]
[paper rustling]
[gemerisik kertas]
[cell phone chimes]
[bunyi telepon seluler]
Ah!
Ah!
[groans]
[mengerang]
-[phone chiming] -[grunts]
-[telepon berbunyi] -[gerutuan]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ musik dramatis dimainkan]
[Kiara] When I studied in Benin,
[Kiara] Ketika saya belajar di Benin,
I realized the Vodún teachings my grandmother gave me
Saya menyadari ajaran Vodún yang diberikan nenek saya kepada saya
connect me to generations of strength, beauty, love.
hubungkan aku dengan generasi kekuatan, keindahan, cinta.
I want to help others change their perspective on Vodún.
Saya ingin membantu orang lain mengubah perspektif mereka tentang Vodún.
Well, then that's what you should write.
Baiklah, itulah yang seharusnya Anda tulis.
Oh, but changing my dissertation course at this point,
Oh, tapi mengubah arah disertasi saya pada titik ini,
that would set us back so much.
Itu akan sangat merugikan kita.
I should just finish it and get a teaching job.
Saya harus menyelesaikannya dan mendapatkan pekerjaan mengajar.
Nah, that's weak.
Nah, itu lemah.
You gotta write what you love.
Anda harus menulis apa yang Anda sukai.
The gym is actually doing really good, so we don't have to worry about it.
Sebenarnya tempat kebugaran itu berjalan sangat baik, jadi kami tidak perlu khawatir.
I got us right now.
Aku paham sekarang.
Then when them bestseller checks start rolling in...
Lalu ketika cek penjualan terbaik mulai mengalir...
[clicks tongue]
[mengklik lidah]
-I'll be your sugar mama? -Mm-hmm.
-Aku mau jadi mama gula kamu? -Mm-hmm.
[Kiara giggles]
[Kiara terkikik]
[Miles] I'ma keep my fade tight and my body right, and that's it.
[Miles] Aku akan menjaga fade-ku tetap kencang dan tubuhku tetap tegak, dan itu saja.
[Kiara] That's all you need to do.
[Kiara] Hanya itu yang perlu kamu lakukan.
[both giggling]
[keduanya terkikik]
I'll keep you around.
Aku akan tetap bersamamu.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ musik dramatis dimainkan]
[cell phone chimes]
[bunyi telepon seluler]
[♪ dramatic music continues]
[♪ musik dramatis berlanjut]
[♪ music intensifies]
[♪ musik semakin intens]
-[door slams] -[♪ music stops]
-[pintu dibanting] -[♪ musik berhenti]
[crickets chirping]
[jangkrik berkicau]
[♪ brooding music playing]
[♪ musik merenung dimainkan]
[Kiara] [voice echoing] The chain that held me together is broken, Miles.
[Kiara] [suara bergema] Rantai yang menyatukanku telah putus, Miles.
I am broken.
Aku hancur.
I can't be fixed.
Saya tidak dapat diperbaiki.
The rituals about strength and protection don't work.
Ritual tentang kekuatan dan perlindungan tidak berhasil.
I don't think I'd be able to carry on without you.
Aku rasa aku tidak dapat bertahan tanpamu.
[Miles] I'd better not mess this up,
[Miles] Sebaiknya aku tidak mengacaukannya,
or you're gonna put a root on me and stick pins in my voodoo doll.
atau kau akan menaruh akarnya padaku dan menusukkan jarum ke boneka voodooku.
Keep joking and you might invite the wrath.
Teruslah bercanda dan Anda mungkin akan mengundang kemarahan.
[both laugh]
[keduanya tertawa]
Is that what you did?
Apakah itu yang kamu lakukan?
You put a root on me?
Kau menaruh akar di tubuhku?
'Cause it does feel like you got me under some kind of spell.
Karena aku merasa seperti kau telah menyihirku dengan sesuatu.
[♪ ominous music playing]
[♪ musik yang tidak menyenangkan dimainkan]
[breathing heavily]
[bernapas berat]
[pen clatters]
[suara pena berdenting]
[chair scrapes]
[gesekan kursi]
[water splashing]
[percikan air]
[faucet squeaking]
[keran berderit]
[Kiara exhales]
[Kiara menghembuskan napas]
[♪ gentle ethereal music playing]
[♪ musik lembut nan halus dimainkan]
[♪ eerie music playing]
[♪ musik menakutkan dimainkan]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ musik dramatis dimainkan]
[screaming]
[teriakan]
[♪ dramatic music continues]
[♪ musik dramatis berlanjut]
[water gurgling]
[air gemericik]
[♪ discordant music playing]
[♪ musik sumbang dimainkan]
[gasping]
[terengah-engah]
Miles?
Mil?
[♪ shaky jazzy music playing]
[♪ Musik jazzy yang bergetar dimainkan]
[Kiara breathing heavily]
[Kiara bernapas berat]
Hello?
Halo?
[♪ jazzy music warbling]
[♪ alunan musik jazzy]
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
[♪ warbling jazz music continues]
[♪ Musik jazz berirama terus berlanjut]
[Kiara gasps]
[Kiara terkesiap]
[♪ music stops]
[♪ musik berhenti]
[faint voices whispering indistinctly]
[suara samar berbisik tak jelas]
[Kiara breathing shakily]
[Kiara bernapas dengan gemetar]
[door creaking open]
[pintu berderit terbuka]
[Kiara gasps]
[Kiara terkesiap]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[suara berbisik tak jelas]
[creaking door closes]
[pintu berderit menutup]
[♪ ominous music playing]
[♪ musik yang tidak menyenangkan dimainkan]
[indistinct voices continue]
[suara tidak jelas terus berlanjut]
[breathing heavily]
[bernapas berat]
-[♪ music stops] -[voices stop]
-[♪ musik berhenti] -[suara berhenti]
-[Kiara sighs] -[crickets chirping]
-[Kiara mendesah] -[jangkrik berkicau]
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
[shaky breathing]
[napas gemetar]
-[objects thud and clatter] -[yelps and gasps]
-[Benda-benda berdentuman dan berdenting] -[Teriak dan terkesiap]
[Kiara panting]
[Kiara terengah-engah]
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
[♪ jazz music resumes playing on record player]
[♪ Musik jazz kembali diputar di pemutar rekaman]
-[knock on door] -[gasps]
-[mengetuk pintu] -[terkesiap]
[♪ music stops abruptly]
[♪ musik berhenti tiba-tiba]
[breathing heavily]
[bernapas berat]
You're not getting my texts?
Kamu tidak menerima pesanku?
I...
SAYA...
There was a...
Ada sebuah...
There was...
Ada...
There was a buzzing sound...
Terdengar suara berdengung...
I came out here and the lights weren't working
Aku datang ke sini dan lampunya tidak menyala
and the door was open, and then...
dan pintunya terbuka, dan kemudian...
And then it wasn't.
Dan kemudian tidak terjadi apa-apa.
But the record player...
Tapi pemutar rekaman...
The record player was playing on its own.
Pemutar rekaman itu memutar lagunya sendiri.
And it wouldn't stop, and...
Dan itu tidak berhenti, dan...
[Miles sighs]
[Miles mendesah]
I swear it was.
Aku bersumpah, begitulah adanya.
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
Look, you obviously have had a lot to drink,
Lihat, kamu jelas sudah minum banyak,
so you're probably just hearing things.
jadi Anda mungkin hanya mendengar sesuatu.
[gasps softly and sighs]
[terengah-engah pelan dan mendesah]
I know what I heard, Miles. It wasn't...
Aku tahu apa yang kudengar, Miles. Itu bukan...
[sniffles]
[mengendus]
Is this you?
Apakah ini kamu?
You thought you'd play a little joke?
Kau pikir kau akan bercanda sedikit?
It's not funny.
Itu tidak lucu.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Saya tidak tahu apa yang Anda bicarakan.
I sent you at least five texts today, telling you
Aku mengirimimu setidaknya lima teks hari ini, memberitahumu
-I was coming to get my things. -[sighing] Oh.
-Aku datang untuk mengambil barang-barangku. -[menghela napas] Oh.
We gotta be outta here so the realtor could show the house over the weekend.
Kita harus keluar dari sini supaya agen properti bisa menunjukkan rumah itu pada akhir pekan.
Where are the boxes with the rest of my shit? Huh?
Di mana kotak-kotak berisi barang-barangku yang lain? Hah?
'Cause I'm not trying to be stuck here forever.
Karena aku tidak ingin terjebak di sini selamanya.
No, you heard it.
Tidak, Anda mendengarnya.
You heard it.
Anda mendengarnya.
-You heard it. -Whoa, Ki, Ki.
-Kau mendengarnya. -Wah, Ki, Ki.
[Kiara groans]
[Kiara mengerang]
Ki, you good?
Ki, kamu baik-baik saja?
Relax, relax. It's fine.
Tenang, tenang. Tidak apa-apa.
Listen, okay? Just sit down.
Dengar, oke? Duduk saja.
-Sit down. -[groans]
-Duduklah. -[erangan]
-Just sit down. -[groaning]
-Duduk saja. -[mengerang]
[♪ tender music playing]
[♪ musik lembut dimainkan]
[Kiara] You're still wearing it.
[Kiara] Kamu masih memakainya.
Yeah. Sometimes it's just easier.
Ya. Terkadang memang lebih mudah.
I should probably stick around for a little bit
Aku mungkin harus bertahan sebentar
and help you get this shit packed and ready to go.
dan membantu Anda mengemas barang-barang ini dan menyiapkannya agar siap berangkat.
[Kiara] Just leave it.
[Kiara] Biarkan saja.
I can do it myself.
Saya bisa melakukannya sendiri.
[Miles] You are not gonna be able to do this yourself.
[Miles] Kamu tidak akan bisa melakukan ini sendiri.
[inhales sharply]
[menarik napas tajam]
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
[Kiara] And you can get rid of that.
[Kiara] Dan kamu bisa menyingkirkannya.
You know that record player was my favorite birthday gift?
Tahukah kamu bahwa pemutar rekaman adalah hadiah ulang tahun favoritku?
It's broken.
Itu rusak.
Just throw it away.
Buang saja.
Nothing lasts forever.
Tak ada yang abadi.
Why don't you just get some sleep, Kiara?
Mengapa kamu tidak tidur saja, Kiara?
I think that's a good idea. I think you should just get some sleep.
Kurasa itu ide bagus. Sebaiknya kamu tidur saja.
[Kiara] I can't sleep.
[Kiara] Aku tidak bisa tidur.
You know that.
Kamu tahu itu.
I never sleep.
Saya tidak pernah tidur.
[♪ tender music continues]
[♪ Musik lembut berlanjut]
[Kiara sighs]
[Kiara mendesah]
[♪ foreboding music playing]
[♪ musik firasat dimainkan]
[crowd cheering faintly]
[kerumunan bersorak pelan]
[announcer] Oakland, California gives us Miles Williams.
[penyiar] Oakland, California memberi kita Miles Williams.
One of the best fighters we've seen out of there in a long time.
Salah satu petarung terbaik yang pernah kita lihat dalam waktu yang lama.
[fists thudding]
[kepalan tangan mengepal]
This is a nightmare matchup.
Ini adalah pertarungan mimpi buruk.
-[grunting] -Oh, he's gotta tap. He's gotta tap.
- [mendengus] -Oh, dia harus mengetuk. Dia harus mengetuk.
-[bone cracking] -[screams]
-[tulang retak] -[teriakan]
[panting]
[terengah-engah]
I mean, you hate to see something happen to that much promise.
Maksudku, Anda benci melihat sesuatu terjadi pada janji sebanyak itu.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ musik dramatis dimainkan]
[entity buzzing]
[entitas berdengung]
[♪ mellow acoustic music playing]
[♪ musik akustik lembut dimainkan]
[buzzing continues]
[suara berdengung terus berlanjut]
[♪ music intensifying]
[♪ musik semakin intensif]
[shrieks]
[menjerit]
[alarm bleeping]
[alarm berbunyi]
[gasps]
[terkesiap]
[gas hissing]
[gas mendesis]
[♪ tense music playing]
[♪ musik menegangkan dimainkan]
[blowing]
[hembusan]
[sizzling]
[mendesis]
[yells]
[berteriak]
-Sabrina? -[garbled chatter]
-Sabrina? -[celoteh tak jelas]
[voice muffled] Sabrina? I'm sorry, I can't understand.
[suara teredam] Sabrina? Maaf, aku tidak mengerti.
Ah! Oh, God!
Ah! Ya Tuhan!
[garbled chatter from phone]
[obrolan tidak jelas dari telepon]
[lights clicking]
[lampu menyala]
[gasps]
[terkesiap]
[♪ tense music playing]
[♪ musik menegangkan dimainkan]
[♪ tense music swells]
[♪ Musik tegang membengkak]
-[♪ music stops abruptly] -[inhales sharply]
-[♪ musik berhenti tiba-tiba] -[menarik napas tajam]
[steady breathing]
[napas teratur]
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
[moans softly]
[mengerang pelan]
[inhales sharply]
[menarik napas tajam]
[groans]
[mengerang]
Miles!
Mil!
[Kiara] [on TV] Milestone, you are my moon.
[Kiara] [di TV] Milestone, kamu adalah bulanku.
With this ring,
Dengan cincin ini,
you join the chain of my ancestors that goes back centuries.
Anda bergabung dengan rantai leluhur saya yang sudah ada sejak berabad-abad lalu.
You fill me with light.
Kau isi aku dengan cahaya.
What's going on here?
Apa yang terjadi di sini?
That's what I would like to know.
Itulah yang ingin saya ketahui.
[Miles] [on TV] ...what I could have possibly done
[Miles] [di TV] ...apa yang mungkin bisa kulakukan
to make me deserve somebody...
untuk membuatku pantas mendapatkan seseorang...
The room didn't just unpack itself, Miles.
Ruangan itu tidak berantakan begitu saja, Miles.
[Kiara sighs]
[Kiara mendesah]
[scoffs] This is insane.
[mencibir] Ini gila.
[Kiara] Well, the movers are gonna be here in 30 minutes,
[Kiara] Baiklah, para tukang pindahan akan tiba dalam 30 menit,
so just...
jadi hanya...
go ahead and go.
lanjutkan saja.
I can help. I used to live here, too.
Saya bisa bantu. Saya dulu tinggal di sini juga.
A lot of help this is.
Ini sangat membantu.
I don't know why you have an attitude.
Saya tidak tahu mengapa Anda bersikap seperti itu.
I'm not the one who spent the whole night reminiscing.
Bukan aku yang menghabiskan sepanjang malam mengenangnya.
I've got an attitude because this broken record player
Saya punya sikap karena pemutar rekaman yang rusak ini
must have sent you a message from the ancestors
pasti telah mengirimimu pesan dari para leluhur
to come and do a bunch of dumb shit
untuk datang dan melakukan banyak hal bodoh
and empty out all the boxes
dan mengosongkan semua kotak
that's supposed to be on the moving truck in 30 minutes.
yang seharusnya berada di truk yang bergerak dalam waktu 30 menit.
-Wow. -Maybe it wasn't the broken record player.
-Wow. -Mungkin bukan pemutar rekaman yang rusak.
Maybe it was the vodka that made you do this dumb-ass shit.
Mungkin vodka yang membuatmu melakukan hal bodoh ini.
Yeah.
Ya.
That's what it was, Miles.
Ya, begitulah adanya, Miles.
It was the vodka.
Itu vodkanya.
It was crazy, drunk Kiara,
Itu gila, Kiara mabuk,
and her masks and her books and her spells.
dan topengnya, buku-bukunya dan mantranya.
Yeah, that's what it was.
Ya, begitulah adanya.
Crazy, drunk Kiara.
Kiara yang gila dan mabuk.
Go on, let crazy Kiara...
Ayo, biarkan Kiara yang gila...
take care of everything
mengurus semuanya
in a drunken stupor.
dalam keadaan mabuk.
Possessed!
Kerasukan!
And completely out of her mind.
Dan benar-benar keluar dari pikirannya.
You know what?
Tahukah kamu?
This is turning into something it don't even need to be right now.
Ini berubah menjadi sesuatu yang bahkan tidak perlu terjadi saat ini.
Ki...
Ke...
obviously, you got something you need to say to me, you want to tell me.
Jelas, ada sesuatu yang ingin kau katakan kepadaku, kau ingin memberitahuku.
You're going about it the wrong way. What's up?
Kamu salah langkah. Ada apa?
No, why don't you use your words, Miles?
Tidak, mengapa kamu tidak menggunakan kata-katamu, Miles?
All I have done is talk and talk and tell you,
Yang kulakukan hanyalah bicara dan bicara serta memberitahumu,
and try to communicate with you, but you don't listen.
dan mencoba berkomunikasi denganmu, tetapi kamu tidak mendengarkan.
You never fucking listen!
Kamu tidak pernah mendengarkan!
-You've never listened! -All I do is listen!
-Kamu tidak pernah mendengarkan! -Aku hanya mendengarkan!
We went to therapy for months,
Kami menjalani terapi selama berbulan-bulan,
and I sat there and I listened, and I listened!
dan aku duduk di sana dan aku mendengarkan, dan aku mendengarkan!
All therapy did was satisfy your hero complex.
Semua terapi itu hanya memuaskan kompleks kepahlawanan Anda.
"Hero complex." "Narcissism."
"Kompleks pahlawan." "Narsisme."
All you did was use therapy to get a bunch of new words to use against me.
Yang kau lakukan hanyalah menggunakan terapi untuk mendapatkan sekumpulan kata-kata baru untuk digunakan melawanku.
You watched the words come out of my mouth,
Kamu menyaksikan kata-kata itu keluar dari mulutku,
and you refused to hear me!
dan kamu menolak mendengarkanku!
I tried to help us move forward. What's so bad about that?
Aku sudah berusaha membantu kita maju. Apa salahnya?
Sorry I couldn't move on.
Maaf, aku tidak bisa melanjutkan hidup.
[softly] I'm sorry you left.
[dengan lembut] Maaf kamu pergi.
[pats stomach]
[menepuk perut]
[Miles] I can't believe you even said that.
[Miles] Aku tak percaya kau mengatakan itu.
You have no idea how hard it was for me to leave.
Anda tidak tahu betapa sulitnya bagi saya untuk pergi.
Oh, really?
Ah, benarkah?
But you still left, Miles.
Tapi kau tetap pergi, Miles.
And now you can pity me from afar and say you didn't crumble.
Dan kini kau bisa mengasihaniku dari jauh dan berkata kau tidak hancur.
You wear it like a fucking badge!
Kau memakainya seperti lencana sialan!
-I ain't even-- -What?
-Aku bahkan tidak-- -Apa?
What?
Apa?
Now you feel guilty?
Sekarang Anda merasa bersalah?
[Kiara scoffs]
[Kiara mencemooh]
I was willing to forgive you, but you let him come between us.
Aku ingin memaafkanmu, tapi kau biarkan dia datang di antara kita.
Fuck you!
Persetan denganmu!
[doorbell rings]
[bel pintu berbunyi]
The movers are here.
Para pengangkut barang sudah ada di sini.
-[sighs] -[doorbell rings]
-[menghela napas] -[bel pintu berbunyi]
[breathing heavily]
[bernapas berat]
[doorbell rings]
[bel pintu berbunyi]
[rattles door handle]
[menggetarkan gagang pintu]
[mover] Mrs. Williams?
[pemindah] Nyonya Williams?
[door handle rattles]
[gagang pintu bergetar]
[exhales]
[menghembuskan napas]
[door rattles]
[suara pintu bergetar]
[doorbell rings]
[bel pintu berbunyi]
This don't make any sense.
Ini tidak masuk akal.
[mover] Mrs. Williams?
[pemindah] Nyonya Williams?
[Miles] Yeah, sorry. Hold on, hold on!
[Miles] Ya, maaf. Tunggu, tunggu!
Try the back door?
Coba lewat pintu belakang?
[♪ tense eerie music playing]
[♪ Musik menegangkan dan menakutkan dimainkan]
-[line ringing] -[sighing] Okay.
-[telepon berdering] -[menghela napas] Oke.
[doorknob rattles]
[gagang pintu berderak]
-You gotta be kidding me. -[doorbell ringing]
-Kamu pasti bercanda. -[bel pintu berbunyi]
[♪ tense eerie music continues]
[♪ Musik menegangkan dan menakutkan terus berlanjut]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[suara berbisik tak jelas]
-It's a nice neighborhood, though. -Yeah.
-Meskipun begitu, itu lingkungan yang bagus. -Ya.
Yeah, yeah. Really quiet.
Ya, ya. Sangat sepi.
[blinds scraping]
[mengikis tirai]
Hey!
Hai!
[mover] I mean, who books movers and doesn't show up? It's crazy, right?
[pindahan] Maksudku, siapa yang pesan jasa pindahan tapi nggak muncul-muncul? Gila, kan?
[pounding on window]
[mengetuk jendela]
Hey! You can't see me?!
Hei! Kamu tidak bisa melihatku?!
-What's the rule? Fifteen minutes? -Yeah.
-Apa aturannya? Lima belas menit? -Ya.
I'm just gonna leave a note.
Saya hanya akan meninggalkan catatan.
-[knocking on window] -[Miles] Wait!
-[mengetuk jendela] -[Miles] Tunggu!
-Don't leave me in here! -[Kiara] Wait!
-Jangan tinggalkan aku di sini! -[Kiara] Tunggu!
[mover] I am sore.
[pemindah] Aku sakit.
[Miles] Move.
[Miles] Minggir.
[grunts]
[mendengus]
[pieces clatter]
[potongan-potongan berdenting]
[breathing heavily]
[bernapas berat]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[suara berbisik tak jelas]
[Miles] Open the door!
[Miles] Buka pintunya!
Open the door!
Buka pintunya!
-[doorknob rattles] -[warbling buzzing noise]
-[gagang pintu berderak] -[suara dengung berkicau]
Open the door!
Buka pintunya!
[Kiara] Do you hear that?
[Kiara] Kau mendengarnya?
I don't hear shit.
Aku tidak mendengar apa pun.
[electricity crackling]
[listrik berderak]
[window blinds thudding]
[tirai jendela berbunyi]
[warbling noise fades out]
[suara riuh menghilang]
[gasps and screams]
[terkesiap dan berteriak]
-Miles! -[screaming]
-Miles! -[berteriak]
[Miles panting]
[Miles terengah-engah]
[Kiara breathing heavily]
[Kiara bernapas berat]
[echoing muffled chuckling]
[menggemakan tawa tertahan]
[♪ gentle music playing]
[♪ musik lembut dimainkan]
I'm about to go change clothes.
Aku hendak pergi berganti pakaian.
[inhales sharply and sighs]
[menarik napas tajam dan mendesah]
[faint warbling and buzzing]
[suara berkicau dan berdengung samar]
[warbling and buzzing continues]
[suara berdengung dan berdengung terus berlanjut]
[faint whispering voices]
[suara berbisik samar]
Hello?
Halo?
[buzzing continues]
[suara berdengung terus berlanjut]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[suara berbisik tak jelas]
[♪ ominous music swelling]
[♪ musik yang tidak menyenangkan membengkak]
[Kiara breathes heavily]
[Kiara bernapas berat]
[gasps]
[terkesiap]
[whimpering]
[merintih]
[laughing]
[tertawa]
[shudders]
[merinding]
[Kiara groans]
[Kiara mengerang]
-[Miles] Kiara. -[gasps]
-[Miles] Kiara. -[terengah-engah]
What are you doing?
Apa yang sedang kamu lakukan?
[breathing shakily]
[bernapas gemetar]
What are you doing? You okay?
Kamu lagi ngapain? Kamu baik-baik saja?
Nothing.
Tidak ada apa-apa.
It's nothing.
Tidak apa-apa.
[sniffles]
[mengendus]
[breathing heavily]
[bernapas berat]
Are you okay?
Apakah kamu baik-baik saja?
[voices whispering]
[suara berbisik]
[Miles] What?
[Miles] Apa?
I don't...
Saya tidak...
I...
SAYA...
Mm, it's nothing. I...
Mm, nggak apa-apa. Aku...
I can't...
Aku tidak bisa...
[Miles] Well, just say it. What?
[Miles] Baiklah, katakan saja. Apa?
I think there's a Vodún spirit in the house.
Saya pikir ada roh Vodún di rumah itu.
No, no, no, no.
Tidak, tidak, tidak, tidak.
Don't start with that.
Jangan mulai dengan itu.
[Kiara] What else could it be, Miles?
[Kiara] Apa lagi yang bisa, Miles?
I remember a legend in Benin...
Saya ingat sebuah legenda di Benin...
about a spirit...
tentang roh...
that traps people in the house.
yang menjebak orang di dalam rumah.
That's bullshit. Just stop.
Omong kosong. Hentikan saja.
I'm not crazy.
Aku tidak gila.
I'm not crazy, Miles.
Aku tidak gila, Miles.
You said so yourself. You don't have faith in that anymore.
Kamu sendiri yang bilang begitu. Kamu sudah tidak percaya lagi.
All the root work this, practitioner shit.
Semua pekerjaan akar ini, omong kosong praktisi.
Your ancestors are connected to love.
Nenek moyang Anda terhubung dengan cinta.
Because if that was true, we wouldn't even be in this situation at all.
Karena jika itu benar, kita tidak akan berada dalam situasi ini sama sekali.
So, do not say that to me.
Jadi, jangan katakan itu padaku.
[breathing heavily]
[bernapas berat]
Think about it, Miles.
Pikirkanlah itu, Miles.
What dragged you across the room?
Apa yang menyeretmu melintasi ruangan?
[Miles sighs]
[Miles mendesah]
[Kiara whimpers]
[Kiara merintih]
You don't have to believe it for it to be true.
Anda tidak harus memercayainya supaya itu menjadi kenyataan.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ musik dramatis dimainkan]
[lighter scratches]
[goresan yang lebih ringan]
[sighs deeply]
[menghela napas dalam-dalam]
[♪ percussive music playing]
[♪ musik perkusi dimainkan]
[flame whooshes]
[api mendesing]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[suara berbisik tak jelas]
[ink scurrying]
[tinta mengalir]
[softly gasps]
[terkesiap pelan]
[book pages flipping]
[membalik halaman buku]
[softly] What?
[dengan lembut] Apa?
[wind howling]
[angin menderu]
[gasping]
[terengah-engah]
[indistinct whispering continues]
[bisikan tak jelas terus berlanjut]
Miles?!
Mil?!
What you in here trying to do? A séance?
Apa yang kau coba lakukan di sini? Sebuah pemanggilan arwah?
Look.
Lihat.
Look at what?
Lihat apa?
You don't see the symbol?
Anda tidak melihat simbolnya?
I see a blank page in a notebook that's on top of a box.
Saya melihat halaman kosong di buku catatan yang ada di atas sebuah kotak.
You can't see it?
Anda tidak dapat melihatnya?
It's a blank page right there.
Itu halaman kosong di sana.
It's the Oya.
Itu Oya.
It represents the African goddess of death and rebirth.
Ini melambangkan dewi kematian dan kelahiran kembali Afrika.
The spirit's trying to communicate with us.
Roh itu mencoba berkomunikasi dengan kita.
And what are you gonna say to it, Ki?
Dan apa yang akan kamu katakan, Ki?
What are you gonna say to this spirit that's trying to communicate?
Apa yang akan Anda katakan kepada roh yang mencoba berkomunikasi ini?
[scoffs]
[mengejek]
-[sighs] -[power drill whirring]
-[menghela napas] -[bor listrik berdengung]
[drill snaps]
[bor berbunyi]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ musik dramatis dimainkan]
Miles.
Mil.
Do not say anything to me
Jangan katakan apapun padaku
unless you have an actual plan that's gonna get us outta here.
kecuali jika Anda punya rencana nyata yang akan membawa kita keluar dari sini.
I already told you what's going on.
Saya sudah beritahu Anda apa yang terjadi.
That's your problem. You never want to deal with real life,
Itu masalahmu. Kamu tidak pernah ingin berurusan dengan kehidupan nyata,
what's actually in front of you.
apa yang sebenarnya ada di depan Anda.
You're saying this is my fault?
Kau bilang ini salahku?
If you would've taken accountability for your actions,
Jika Anda mau bertanggung jawab atas tindakan Anda,
we would've never ended up in this situation at all.
kita tidak akan pernah berakhir dalam situasi ini sama sekali.
You literally burnt down every single thing that we built together.
Anda benar-benar membakar habis setiap hal yang telah kita bangun bersama.
Is that it?
Hanya itu saja?
Or is it the fact that every time something gets too hard,
Atau apakah itu fakta bahwa setiap kali sesuatu menjadi terlalu sulit,
you give up?
kamu menyerah?
Coward.
Pengecut.
-I'm a fucking coward? -Yeah.
-Aku pengecut sialan? -Ya.
Good luck dealing with all the shit
Semoga beruntung menghadapi semua masalah ini
that's happening in this house by yourself.
Itu yang terjadi di rumah ini sendirian.
And when this whole thing is over, we never have to see each other again.
Dan ketika semua ini berakhir, kita tidak perlu bertemu lagi.
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[suara berbisik tak jelas]
[warbling buzzing]
[kicau berdengung]
What?
Apa?
What now? What?
Sekarang apa? Apa?
-[high-pitched alarm bleeping] -Goddamn!
-[bunyi alarm bernada tinggi] -Sialan!
[static crackles]
[suara berderak statis]
-[explosions booming] -[Kiara yelps]
-[ledakan menggelegar] -[Kiara berteriak]
[Miles] Oh, shit.
[Miles] Oh, sial.
[rattling]
[berderak]
[Kiara gasping]
[Kiara terengah-engah]
[Kiara] Oh, shit.
[Kiara] Oh, sial.
[alarm beeping continues]
[alarm berbunyi terus menerus]
[voices whispering]
[suara berbisik]
-[objects clattering] -Get down!
-[Benda berdenting] -Turun!
[Kiara gasps]
[Kiara terkesiap]
[dishes shattering]
[piring pecah]
[Kiara panting]
[Kiara terengah-engah]
[♪ smooth jazz music playing on record player]
[♪ Musik jazz lembut diputar di pemutar rekaman]
[Kiara] [whispering] Miles.
[Kiara] [berbisik] Miles.
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[suara berbisik tak jelas]
[♪ jazz music fading]
[♪ musik jazz memudar]
[♪ somber music playing]
[♪ musik sedih dimainkan]
[paper rustling]
[gemerisik kertas]
[Miles] "Dear Ki,
[Miles] "Ki yang terkasih,
"AKA, Ki Money.
"alias, Ki Money."
I can't believe you done broke me down to a guy who writes love letters."
Aku tak percaya kau hancurkan aku menjadi lelaki yang menulis surat cinta.
[announcer] Williams has gotta get his head off the line.
[penyiar] Williams harus melepaskan kepalanya dari garis itu.
[both grunting]
[keduanya mendengus]
[crowd cheering]
[penonton bersorak]
[spectator 1] Let's go, Mayhem!
[penonton 1] Ayo, Mayhem!
-[fist thudding] -[Miles groaning]
-[tinjunya terkepal] -[Miles mengerang]
[both grunting]
[keduanya mendengus]
[crowd shouting]
[kerumunan berteriak]
[Miles groaning]
[Miles mengerang]
[spectator 2] Get up, Williams!
[penonton 2] Bangun, Williams!
[announcer] That's a gator walk into a guillotine.
[penyiar] Itu seperti buaya yang berjalan menuju guillotine.
That is a recipe for nighty-nights.
Itu resep untuk tidur nyenyak.
[both grunting]
[keduanya mendengus]
[cage rattling]
[suara kandang berderak]
[high-pitched tone ringing]
[suara bernada tinggi]
-[spectator 3] Come on, Mayhem! -[bell dings]
-[penonton 3] Ayo, Mayhem! -[bel berbunyi]
[referee] Time! Done.
[wasit] Waktunya! Selesai.
[echoing] To your corners! To your corners!
[bergema] Ke sudut-sudutmu! Ke sudut-sudutmu!
[Miles sighing]
[Miles mendesah]
[spectator 4] Get up, Williams! Let's go! Come on, Mayhem!
[Penonton 4] Bangun, Williams! Ayo! Ayo, Mayhem!
[crowd shouting]
[kerumunan berteriak]
[voice muffled and echoing] Get your head up and hit him.
[suara teredam dan bergema] Angkat kepalamu dan pukul dia.
You get him on the floor
Kau menjatuhkannya ke lantai
and then throw some punches.
dan kemudian melontarkan beberapa pukulan.
Use that to your advantage...
Gunakan itu untuk keuntungan Anda...
[Miles] "And you know I'm no James Baldwin or Kiara Guillory
[Miles] "Dan kau tahu aku bukan James Baldwin atau Kiara Guillory
"with the words, you feel me?
"dengan kata-kata itu, kau merasakannya?
"But the first time I saw you,
"Tapi pertama kali aku melihatmu,
I knew I didn't want to spend another day without you in my life."
Aku tahu aku tidak ingin menghabiskan hari lagi tanpamu dalam hidupku."
[coach] [echoing] Just give him a taste of his own medicine.
[pelatih] [menggemakan] Beri dia kesempatan untuk merasakan sendiri efek obatnya.
Put him on his back.
Baringkan dia dalam keadaan telentang.
Keep him on his feet. Push him off...
Biarkan dia berdiri. Dorong dia...
-[bell dings] -You got this.
-[bel berbunyi] -Kamu bisa melakukannya.
[grunts]
[mendengus]
-[fists thudding] -[fighters grunting]
-[tinju berdebar] -[petarung mendengus]
[crowd shouting]
[kerumunan berteriak]
[fighters yell]
[para petarung berteriak]
[announcer] I don't know who this guy is.
[penyiar] Saya tidak tahu siapa orang ini.
His cornerman's gotta be really proud of him.
Penjaga sudutnya pasti sangat bangga padanya.
[punches thudding]
[pukulan yang berdebar]
He's now got his head off the line.
Sekarang kepalanya sudah tidak berada di garis batas.
He's bobbing and weaving.
Dia mengangguk-angguk dan bergoyang.
[both grunting]
[keduanya mendengus]
[fists and kicks thudding]
[tinju dan tendangan yang berdebar]
He's the guy we thought we were gonna see.
Dialah orang yang kami pikir akan kami temui.
[kick thudding]
[tendangan berdebar]
Yeah, well, he's setting him up with a double leg.
Ya, baiklah, dia menjebaknya dengan kaki ganda.
-[body thuds] -And he dunked him.
-[Benda berbenturan] -Dan dia mencelupkannya.
And now ground and pound.
Dan sekarang digiling dan ditumbuk.
That's the opposite guy than we saw before.
Itu orang yang berkebalikan dari yang kita lihat sebelumnya.
Ground and pound again.
Giling dan pukul lagi.
-[punches thudding] -[crowd shouting]
-[pukulan keras] -[kerumunan berteriak]
[Miles groans]
[Miles mengerang]
[announcer] Well, here comes a rear naked choke.
[penyiar] Nah, ini dia kuncian rear naked choke.
[crowd cheering and shouting]
[kerumunan bersorak dan berteriak]
[fighter wincing]
[petarung meringis]
Way to go, Miles Williams.
Hebat, Miles Williams.
-[bell dinging] -That's a heck of a good fight.
-[bel berbunyi] -Itu pertarungan yang sangat hebat.
[Miles sighs]
[Miles mendesah]
[Miles] "I was training today,
[Miles] "Saya sedang berlatih hari ini,
-"and I couldn't stop thinking about you. -[both laughing]
-"dan aku tidak bisa berhenti memikirkanmu. -[keduanya tertawa]
"Like, why is this happening to me?
"Seperti, mengapa ini terjadi padaku?
"It's crazy to be thinking about one person this much.
"Gila sekali memikirkan satu orang sebanyak ini.
"Is this normal?
"Apakah ini normal?
[Kiara giggling]
[Kiara terkikik]
"You're a mysterious vibe I just can't quite put my finger on.
"Kamu adalah aura misterius yang tidak dapat aku jelaskan dengan tepat.
"I feel like I'ma drown in your depth.
"Aku merasa seperti tenggelam dalam kedalamanmu.
"I wish I understood it.
"Saya harap saya memahaminya.
But maybe it's better I can't."
Tapi mungkin lebih baik aku tidak bisa."
[♪ gentle music playing]
[♪ musik lembut dimainkan]
Slip. Slip.
Tergelincir. Tergelincir.
Now remember, you gotta keep your hands up. Come on. Uh!
Ingat, kamu harus tetap angkat tangan. Ayo. Uh!
"I admire your spirit, Ki."
"Aku mengagumi semangatmu, Ki."
-[Kiara grunting] -Oh!
-[Kiara mendengus] -Oh!
"It's so free.
"Sangat gratis.
[laughter]
[tawa]
"It's scary how much I'm wrapped into you.
"Menakutkan sekali betapa aku terbungkus dalam dirimu.
You know you got me."
Kau tahu kau berhasil menangkapku.
[Kiara sighs]
[Kiara mendesah]
[Miles] "I love you."
[Miles] "Aku mencintaimu."
[Kiara sniffling]
[Kiara terisak]
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
[sniffles]
[mengendus]
[Kiara] "My Milestone.
[Kiara] "Tonggak Sejarah Saya.
"I fancy myself a writer, but when I try to find the words
“Saya membayangkan diri saya sebagai seorang penulis, tetapi ketika saya mencoba menemukan kata-kata
"to express how you make me feel,
"untuk mengungkapkan bagaimana kamu membuatku merasa,
"words fail me.
"kata-kata tak mampu menggambarkanku.
"That's how you know it's true love.
"Begitulah cara Anda mengetahui itu cinta sejati.
"When I look into your eyes, the world falls away.
"Saat aku menatap matamu, dunia seakan runtuh.
"Time stops,
"Waktu berhenti,
"and I find myself gazing at my wildest dream.
"dan aku mendapati diriku tengah menatap mimpiku yang terliar.
"One I never want to wake up from.
"Yang satu ini, yang tidak ingin aku bangun lagi.
"A dream I want to last forever.
"Mimpi yang ingin kujalani selamanya.
"A dream where I can take flight
"Mimpi dimana aku bisa terbang
"and soar to the highest heights in the safety of your arms,
"dan terbang ke ketinggian tertinggi dengan aman dalam pelukanmu,
"where nothing can hurt me.
"di mana tidak ada yang dapat menyakitiku.
[sniffles]
[mengendus]
"And then you smile...
"Dan kemudian kamu tersenyum...
"and I fall in love all over again.
"dan aku jatuh cinta lagi.
"No one has ever loved me the way you do.
"Tidak ada seorang pun yang pernah mencintaiku seperti kamu.
"I love you.
"Aku mencintaimu.
You are my moon."
"Kamu adalah bulanku."
[low rumbling]
[gemuruh rendah]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[suara berbisik tak jelas]
[floorboards creaking]
[papan lantai berderit]
[♪ menacing music playing]
[♪ musik mengancam dimainkan]
[Miles] Kiara.
[Miles] Kiara.
[wood creaking]
[kayu berderit]
[warbled buzzing intensifies]
[dengungan berdengung semakin intensif]
[buzzing fades]
[dengungan memudar]
Kiara.
Kiara.
[♪ menacing music continues]
[♪ musik yang mengancam berlanjut]
[child's laughter]
[tawa anak-anak]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[suara berbisik tak jelas]
-[fists thudding] -[chains rattling]
-[tinju berdebar] -[rantai berderak]
[fists thudding]
[kepalan tangan mengepal]
Hey.
Hai.
[chains rattling]
[rantai berderak]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ musik dramatis dimainkan]
[Kiara gasps]
[Kiara terkesiap]
[faucet squeaking]
[keran berderit]
[gasping]
[terengah-engah]
[fists thudding]
[kepalan tangan mengepal]
[♪ dramatic music intensifies]
[♪ musik dramatis semakin intens]
[screaming]
[teriakan]
[gasps]
[terkesiap]
[panting]
[terengah-engah]
This can't be real.
Ini tidak mungkin nyata.
[screaming]
[teriakan]
-Ki! -[yelling]
-Ki! -[berteriak]
-[bone cracks] -[gasps]
-[retakan tulang] -[terkesiap]
-[water splashes] -[muffled screams]
-[percikan air] -[jeritan teredam]
[demonic chuckle]
[tertawa setan]
[muffled screaming continues]
[teriakan teredam terus berlanjut]
[both grunting]
[keduanya mendengus]
[growling]
[menggeram]
[♪ tense music playing]
[♪ musik menegangkan dimainkan]
[gasps]
[terkesiap]
[raspy sigh]
[desahan serak]
[water gurgling]
[air gemericik]
[♪ tense music continues]
[♪ Musik tegang berlanjut]
[both grunting]
[keduanya mendengus]
[♪ music stops]
[♪ musik berhenti]
[coughing]
[batuk]
[groans]
[mengerang]
[breathing heavily]
[bernapas berat]
[screams]
[berteriak]
[yelps]
[keluhan]
[choked gasping]
[tersedak dan terengah-engah]
[♪ tense music swelling]
[♪ musik tegang membengkak]
[heartbeat thumping]
[detak jantung berdebar]
[Kiara gasps]
[Kiara terkesiap]
[heartbeat thumping louder]
[detak jantung semakin kencang]
[choking]
[tersedak]
[spitting]
[meludah]
[gasps]
[terkesiap]
[coughing]
[batuk]
[♪ tense music continues]
[♪ Musik tegang berlanjut]
[both grunting]
[keduanya mendengus]
Ah!
Ah!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Tidak, tidak, tidak, tidak, tidak, tidak!
-[bones cracking] -[screams]
-[tulang retak] -[teriakan]
[demonic cackle]
[tertawa setan]
[screaming]
[teriakan]
[♪ ominous music playing]
[♪ musik yang tidak menyenangkan dimainkan]
[whispering] Ki.
[berbisik] Untuk.
You gotta keep your hands up.
Kamu harus tetap mengangkat tanganmu.
Miles.
Mil.
[whispering] You're my North Star.
[berbisik] Kaulah Bintang Utaraku.
[Kiara sighs]
[Kiara mendesah]
[gasps]
[terkesiap]
Miles.
Mil.
[softly] Wait.
[dengan lembut] Tunggu.
[gasps softly]
[terengah-engah pelan]
-[♪ music stops] -[sighs]
-[♪ musik berhenti] -[menghela napas]
[warbled buzzing]
[berdengung berkicau]
[♪ ominous music playing]
[♪ musik yang tidak menyenangkan dimainkan]
[wet footsteps squelching]
[langkah kaki basah berdecit]
[buzzing intensifies]
[dengungan semakin kuat]
[wet footsteps]
[langkah kaki basah]
[buzzing continues]
[suara berdengung terus berlanjut]
[♪ ominous music continues]
[♪ Musik yang tidak menyenangkan berlanjut]
[buzzing fades]
[dengungan memudar]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[suara berbisik tak jelas]
-[♪ music stops abruptly] -[gasps]
-[♪ musik berhenti tiba-tiba] -[terkesiap]
[heartbeat thumping]
[detak jantung berdebar]
Ki.
Ke.
[door closes]
[pintu tertutup]
[footsteps]
[langkah kaki]
[Miles sighs]
[Miles mendesah]
Kiara.
Kiara.
Wake up.
Bangun.
Hey. Wake up.
Hei. Bangun.
Ki.
Ke.
-Kiara. Kiara, you okay? -[Kiara groaning]
-Kiara. Kiara, kamu baik-baik saja? -[Kiara mengerang]
[Kiara groans]
[Kiara mengerang]
Oh, goddamn.
Oh, sialan.
[inhales sharply]
[menarik napas tajam]
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
Oh, I have a headache.
Aduh, kepala saya sakit.
Of course you do.
Tentu saja.
You were probably drinking all day.
Anda mungkin minum sepanjang hari.
People get headaches when they just lay in the house
Orang-orang mengalami sakit kepala ketika mereka hanya berbaring di rumah
and fucking drink all day.
dan minum sepanjang hari.
What's wrong now?
Apa yang salah sekarang?
What do you think is wrong, Ki?
Menurutmu apa yang salah, Ki?
-[Kiara sighs] -You laying there, stiff.
-[Kiara mendesah] -Kamu terbaring di sana, kaku.
I can't even tell if you breathing or not. I thought you...
Aku bahkan tidak tahu apakah kamu bernapas atau tidak. Kupikir kamu...
You thought what?
Kamu pikir apa?
[Kiara chuckles]
[Kiara terkekeh]
No. Sorry, baby.
Tidak. Maaf, sayang.
-It's not your lucky day. -Stop.
-Ini bukan hari keberuntunganmu. -Berhenti.
[Kiara] Stop what?
[Kiara] Hentikan apa?
"Stop, stop. Stop breathing."
"Berhenti, berhenti. Berhenti bernapas."
-[laughs] -Ki.
-[tertawa] -Kunci.
-Please. Ki-- -Mm, that'd be a dream come true.
-Kumohon. Ki-- -Mm, itu akan menjadi mimpi yang jadi kenyataan.
[laughs]
[tertawa]
-Why are you doing this to yourself? -Doing what?
-Mengapa kau lakukan ini pada dirimu sendiri? -Melakukan apa?
Can't take a nap. Can't have a drink.
Nggak bisa tidur siang. Nggak bisa minum.
[liquid pouring]
[menuangkan cairan]
Have a drink with me.
Minumlah bersamaku.
[bottle thuds]
[botol berdentuman]
I cannot keep living like this, Ki.
Aku tidak bisa terus-terusan hidup seperti ini, Ki.
I'm telling you, I cannot keep doing this.
Saya katakan padamu, saya tidak bisa terus melakukan ini.
We gotta figure something out.
Kita harus menemukan jalan keluar.
'Cause this?
Karena ini?
It has to stop.
Ini harus dihentikan.
You can't?
Kamu tidak bisa?
Then don't.
Kalau begitu, jangan lakukan itu.
[♪ gentle melancholy music playing]
[♪ musik melankolis lembut dimainkan]
[Kiara moans]
[Kiara mengerang]
[clothing rustling]
[gemerisik pakaian]
[bag zippering]
[menutup ritsleting tas]
Where are you going?
Kamu mau pergi ke mana?
-[kiss smack] -[Kiara moans]
-[ciuman lembut] -[Kiara mengerang]
Where are you going?
Kamu mau pergi ke mana?
Miles?
Mil?
Stop.
Berhenti.
[tearfully] Miles.
[sambil menangis] Miles.
Miles!
Mil!
My Milestone.
Tonggak Sejarah Saya.
[♪ gentle melancholy music continues playing]
[♪ Musik melankolis lembut terus dimainkan]
[Miles] Don't do that.
[Miles] Jangan lakukan itu.
Don't do that to me.
Jangan lakukan itu padaku.
[Kiara sighs]
[Kiara mendesah]
If I stay, then what?
Jika aku tinggal, lalu bagaimana?
What will it be...
Akan apa...
if I stay?
jika saya tinggal?
[Kiara scoffs]
[Kiara mencemooh]
Fine.
Bagus.
You wanna go?
Kamu mau pergi?
Go.
Pergi.
[sniffles]
[mengendus]
[crickets chirping]
[jangkrik berkicau]
[Kiara sobbing]
[Kiara terisak]
[exhales sharply]
[menghembuskan napas tajam]
[sniffles]
[mengendus]
[breathing heavily]
[bernapas berat]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ musik dramatis dimainkan]
-I'm sorry. -Miles.
-Maafkan aku. -Miles.
Miles. Miles!
Mil. Mil!
-[♪ music stops] -[both gasp]
-[♪ musik berhenti] -[keduanya terkesiap]
[both panting]
[keduanya terengah-engah]
How did I get right here?
Bagaimana saya bisa sampai di sini?
[sighs] I...
[menghela napas] Aku...
You're okay.
Kamu baik-baik saja.
[Miles sighs]
[Miles mendesah]
I don't...
Saya tidak...
What are you doing?
Apa yang sedang kamu lakukan?
What is that?
Apa itu?
This is my grandmother's book of spells.
Ini adalah buku mantra nenekku.
These are all unfinished.
Ini semua belum selesai.
Oh, Miles. I don't know.
Oh, Miles. Aku tidak tahu.
[Kiara sighs]
[Kiara mendesah]
There's my mom's handwriting.
Itu tulisan tangan ibuku.
Looks like she was trying to translate some notes.
Tampaknya dia mencoba menerjemahkan beberapa catatan.
[sighs] She used to do these meditations.
[menghela napas] Dia biasa melakukan meditasi ini.
-Like rituals? -Yeah, like healing rituals.
-Seperti ritual? -Ya, seperti ritual penyembuhan.
But I was so young when she died, I...
Tapi saya masih sangat muda saat dia meninggal, saya...
never really held on to it.
tidak pernah benar-benar memegangnya.
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
[softly] She was a great teacher.
[dengan lembut] Dia adalah seorang guru yang hebat.
Yeah, I wish I could have met her.
Ya, aku harap aku bisa bertemu dengannya.
She would've loved you.
Dia pasti mencintaimu.
I tried to conjure her spirit once, when I was 16.
Aku pernah mencoba memanggil arwahnya, saat aku berusia 16 tahun.
I wasn't powerful enough.
Saya tidak cukup kuat.
Did you ever try to conjure another spirit?
Pernahkah Anda mencoba memanggil roh lain?
No.
TIDAK.
Hold on.
Tunggu.
[♪ brooding music playing]
[♪ musik merenung dimainkan]
What?
Apa?
[sighs] I can't believe I was gonna give this away.
[menghela napas] Aku tak percaya aku akan membocorkan ini.
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
The notes say millet flour...
Catatannya mengatakan tepung millet...
water...
air...
and something personal,
dan sesuatu yang pribadi,
like this amethyst necklace my mom gave me...
seperti kalung batu kecubung yang diberikan ibuku padaku...
[turns tap water on]
[menyalakan air keran]
...could help lead me to my ancestors.
...bisa membantuku menemui leluhurku.
[stove burner clicking, gas hisses]
[kompor berbunyi klik, gas mendesis]
I found our old love letters.
Aku menemukan surat cinta lama kita.
Oh, no. How corny were they?
Oh, tidak. Betapa noraknya mereka?
[chuckles softly]
[tertawa kecil]
-They were really sweet. -So, super corny?
-Mereka sungguh manis. -Jadi, super norak?
[laughs]
[tertawa]
They reminded me of how we used to be.
Mereka mengingatkanku pada masa lalu kita.
When did we stop fighting for each other like that?
Kapan kita berhenti bertengkar satu sama lain seperti itu?
[kettle whistling]
[ketel bersiul]
[whistling peters out]
[siulan menghilang]
[♪ tender music playing]
[♪ musik lembut dimainkan]
[kettle clatters]
[suara ketel berdenting]
We should get started.
Kita harus memulai.
-Is this that sage shit? -Yeah.
-Apakah ini omong kosong orang bijak? -Ya.
I know you don't like it,
Aku tahu kamu tidak menyukainya,
but the notes say we need to stay open and receive.
tetapi catatan itu mengatakan kita perlu tetap terbuka dan menerima.
[breathing deeply]
[bernapas dalam-dalam]
We never know what will be revealed in this realm.
Kita tidak pernah tahu apa yang akan terungkap di alam ini.
[spoon clinking]
[sendok berdenting]
Are you sure you want to do this?
Apakah Anda yakin ingin melakukan ini?
[sighs softly]
[menghela napas pelan]
[Kiara slurps]
[Kiara menyeruput]
[Kiara] We give thanks to the ancestors and the most high.
[Kiara] Kami mengucapkan terima kasih kepada para leluhur dan yang maha tinggi.
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
Focus on our connections to the moments.
Berfokuslah pada hubungan kita dengan momen-momen tersebut.
The song.
Lagu itu.
The visions.
Visi-visi.
The chaos. All of it.
Kekacauan. Semuanya.
What do you need us to know? What are you trying to tell us?
Apa yang ingin Anda sampaikan kepada kami?
[wind rumbles faintly]
[angin bergemuruh pelan]
[air whooshes]
[udara mendesing]
[chimes clacking]
[lonceng berdenting]
[liquid splashes]
[percikan cairan]
[♪ tense music playing]
[♪ musik menegangkan dimainkan]
[entity breathing deeply]
[entitas bernapas dalam-dalam]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[suara berbisik tak jelas]
Ki, what's wrong?
Ki, ada apa?
[groans softly]
[mengerang pelan]
[indistinct whispering continues]
[bisikan tak jelas terus berlanjut]
[Kiara wheezes]
[Kiara terengah-engah]
[warbled buzzing]
[berdengung berkicau]
[chair scrapes]
[gesekan kursi]
[♪ tense music continues]
[♪ Musik tegang berlanjut]
Ki, are you okay?
Ki, kamu baik-baik saja?
-[table scrapes] -Oh, shit!
-[menggaruk meja] -Oh, sial!
[♪ tense music swelling]
[♪ musik tegang membengkak]
Kiara.
Kiara.
[Miles screams]
[Miles berteriak]
[grunts]
[mendengus]
Ki!
Siapa!
[♪ music intensifying]
[♪ musik semakin intensif]
[♪ music fades out]
[♪ musik memudar]
[birds tweeting]
[burung berkicau]
[♪ gentle music playing]
[♪ musik lembut dimainkan]
[♪ ethereal music playing]
[♪ musik halus dimainkan]
[breathing shakily]
[bernapas gemetar]
Am I dead?
Apakah saya sudah mati?
[Entity] [voice echoing] No. You're in our sacred place.
[Entitas] [suara bergema] Tidak. Anda berada di tempat suci kami.
It's not your time to join us yet.
Sekarang belum saatnya Anda bergabung dengan kami.
Who are you?
Siapa kamu?
[Entity] [echoing] I'm a link in the chain of the Guillory women
[Entitas] [bergema] Aku adalah mata rantai dari para wanita Guillory
that live yesterday, today, and tomorrow.
yang hidup kemarin, hari ini, dan esok.
[gasping]
[terengah-engah]
I'm so lost.
Aku sungguh tersesat.
[Entity] [echoing] You know you must rejoin the chain.
[Entitas] [bergema] Anda tahu Anda harus bergabung kembali dengan rantai tersebut.
But you can't do it alone.
Namun Anda tidak dapat melakukannya sendirian.
The moon needs its star.
Bulan membutuhkan bintangnya.
All that you need is sitting beside you now.
Yang Anda butuhkan sekarang ada di samping Anda.
All you have to do is listen.
Yang perlu Anda lakukan hanyalah mendengarkan.
[echoing] Listen...
[bergema] Dengarkan...
[♪ ethereal music continues]
[♪ musik halus terus berlanjut]
[voices whispering indistinctly]
[suara berbisik tak jelas]
It's time for you to truly embrace us.
Sudah saatnya bagi Anda untuk benar-benar merangkul kami.
[♪ music stops]
[♪ musik berhenti]
[drawer rattling open]
[laci berderak terbuka]
[Kiara] "Dear Miles.
[Kiara] "Miles yang terkasih.
"I failed you.
"Aku mengecewakanmu.
"I failed us.
"Aku mengecewakan kita.
"The story wasn't supposed to end this way,
“Ceritanya tidak seharusnya berakhir seperti ini,
"but the weight of it all is unbearable.
"tetapi beban itu semua tak tertahankan.
"I don't wanna be here anymore.
"Saya tidak ingin berada di sini lagi.
[inhales sharply]
[menarik napas tajam]
"I have to end it all.
"Saya harus mengakhiri semuanya.
I'm so sorry."
"Saya sangat menyesal."
I think I found a way for us to get out of here, Miles.
Kurasa aku menemukan cara bagi kita untuk keluar dari sini, Miles.
You wanna kill yourself?
Kau ingin bunuh diri?
Where are you going?
Kamu mau pergi ke mana?
I find your suicide note, and you don't wanna talk about it?
Aku menemukan catatan bunuh dirimu, dan kamu tidak mau membicarakannya?
Ki.
Ke.
Ki?
Di mana?
So, what was all this for?
Jadi, untuk apa semua ini?
Was it just a show?
Apakah itu hanya sebuah pertunjukan?
All the packing and the selling the house?
Semua pengepakan dan penjualan rumah?
I took care of everything.
Saya mengurus semuanya.
I did everything, so that you wouldn't have to worry about anything.
Aku melakukan segalanya, agar kamu tidak perlu khawatir tentang apa pun.
You did not take care of everything. You took care of everything except you.
Kamu tidak mengurus semuanya. Kamu mengurus semuanya kecuali dirimu sendiri.
I...
SAYA...
I couldn't--
Aku tidak bisa--
[laughs shakily]
[tertawa gemetar]
There was nothing left to take care of, Miles.
Tidak ada lagi yang perlu diurus, Miles.
[Kiara sniffling]
[Kiara terisak]
I was devastated every morning...
Saya hancur setiap pagi...
because I woke up from the night before.
karena aku terbangun dari malam sebelumnya.
Do you know what that's like?
Tahukah Anda seperti apa itu?
I hate who I am.
Aku benci diriku sendiri.
[whispering] I can't stand to look at myself.
[berbisik] Aku tak tahan melihat diriku sendiri.
[normal] I am not the same person you married.
[normal] Aku bukan orang yang sama dengan yang kamu nikahi.
That's okay.
Tidak apa-apa.
I'm not the same man that you married.
Aku bukan pria yang sama dengan yang kamu nikahi.
I just wanted you to come to me.
Aku hanya ingin kau datang padaku.
That's it.
Itu saja.
[sniffles]
[mengendus]
I gotta finish this.
Aku harus menyelesaikan ini.
[♪ gentle intriguing music playing]
[♪ musik lembut yang menarik dimainkan]
I know you don't believe any of this.
Saya tahu Anda tidak percaya semua ini.
Whatever's in this house needs to know we honor it.
Apa pun yang ada di rumah ini perlu tahu bahwa kita menghormatinya.
Bring the bottle tree so the evil spirits know to stay away.
Bawalah pohon botol sehingga roh jahat tahu untuk menjauh.
[bottles clinking softly]
[botol berdenting pelan]
[salt pouring]
[menuangkan garam]
The Nyame Dua will tell our ancestors we need their protection.
Nyame Dua akan memberi tahu leluhur kita bahwa kita membutuhkan perlindungan mereka.
Crystals will channel our connection.
Kristal akan menyalurkan koneksi kita.
The circle of my mother's salt.
Lingkaran garam ibuku.
Candles will light our way.
Lilin akan menerangi jalan kita.
Join me in the circle.
Bergabunglah denganku dalam lingkaran itu.
[match scratches, sizzles]
[goresan korek api, bunyi mendesis]
I'll try and remember the dance I saw in Benin
Saya akan mencoba mengingat tarian yang saya lihat di Benin
that helped the matriarchs connect with their spirits.
yang membantu para matriark terhubung dengan roh mereka.
[exhales slowly]
[menghembuskan napas perlahan]
[♪ brooding music playing]
[♪ musik merenung dimainkan]
[inhales deeply]
[menarik napas dalam-dalam]
[exhales]
[menghembuskan napas]
[♪ suspenseful percussive music playing]
[♪ musik perkusi yang menegangkan dimainkan]
[♪ ethereal music playing]
[♪ musik halus dimainkan]
[♪ mellow jazz music playing on record player]
[♪ Musik jazz lembut diputar di pemutar rekaman]
[Kiara] I think you're gonna like how this night ends.
[Kiara] Aku pikir kamu akan menyukai bagaimana malam ini berakhir.
I have a surprise for you.
Saya punya kejutan untuk Anda.
Suspense.
Ketegangan.
[both laughing]
[keduanya tertawa]
Alright, what?
Baiklah, apa?
I love you.
Aku mencintaimu.
I love you, too.
Aku pun mencintaimu.
I love you so much.
Aku sangat mencintaimu.
[inhales deeply and sighs]
[menarik napas dalam-dalam dan mendesah]
[voice breaking] You are my moon, Milestone.
[suara terputus-putus] Kaulah bulanku, Milestone.
And we are so blessed to have this marriage and this love.
Dan kami sangat diberkati memiliki pernikahan dan cinta ini.
[Kiara chuckles]
[Kiara terkekeh]
I-- I feel like the luckiest woman in the world.
Aku--aku merasa seperti wanita paling beruntung di dunia.
And now...
Dan sekarang...
we get to grow our tribe.
kita bisa mengembangkan suku kita.
[Kiara chuckles]
[Kiara terkekeh]
Are we pregnant?
Apakah kita hamil?
-[gasps] -[Kiara laughs]
-[terkesiap] -[Kiara tertawa]
Wait, let me see. Hold on!
Tunggu, biar kulihat. Tunggu!
You-- You can't hear the heartbeat yet.
Kamu-- Kamu belum bisa mendengar detak jantungnya.
-[laughs] -My child has a strong heartbeat.
-[tertawa] -Anak saya detak jantungnya kuat.
I could probably hear it.
Saya mungkin bisa mendengarnya.
[water bubbling and rushing]
[air menggelegak dan mengalir deras]
[waves crashing]
[ombak menghantam]
[voice muffled] My God, I love you so much.
[suara teredam] Ya Tuhan, aku sangat mencintaimu.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ musik dramatis dimainkan]
[child laughing]
[anak tertawa]
[heartbeat thumping]
[detak jantung berdebar]
[laughing]
[tertawa]
[mimics an airplane]
[meniru pesawat terbang]
Come in for a water landing.
Datang untuk pendaratan di air.
Okay, Jeremiah! It's party time. Let's get you dressed.
Oke, Jeremiah! Waktunya berpesta. Ayo kita pakaikan bajumu.
Aw, Mom, can I swim for a little bit longer, please?
Ah, Bu, bolehkah aku berenang sedikit lebih lama lagi?
-Please? -[Kiara laughs]
-Tolong? -[Kiara tertawa]
[Miles chuckles]
[Miles terkekeh]
[Kiara] You wanna open up one of your gifts early?
[Kiara] Kamu mau membuka salah satu hadiahmu lebih awal?
-[Kiara] Happy birthday! -[Miles] Happy birthday!
-[Kiara] Selamat ulang tahun! -[Miles] Selamat ulang tahun!
It's a Bell P-39 Airacobra remote-control plane!
Itu pesawat kendali jarak jauh Bell P-39 Airacobra!
[Kiara] Yes, it is!
[Kiara] Ya, benar!
[Jeremiah Williams] Now I can practice all my flight maneuvers!
[Jeremiah Williams] Sekarang saya dapat melatih semua manuver penerbangan saya!
-[imitating air whooshing] -[Kiara] Whoo!
-[menirukan desiran udara] -[Kiara] Whoo!
[imitating airplane engine buzzing]
[menirukan dengungan mesin pesawat]
[camera shutters click]
[suara rana kamera berbunyi]
[♪ gentle music playing]
[♪ musik lembut dimainkan]
[giggles]
[tertawa kecil]
It's just like the Tuskegee Airmen.
Sama seperti Tuskegee Airmen.
I've always wanted one! Thank you. I love you so much.
Aku selalu menginginkannya! Terima kasih. Aku sangat mencintaimu.
-We love you, J. -Aw.
-Kami mencintaimu, J. -Ah.
[laughs] We love you, baby.
[tertawa] Kami mencintaimu, sayang.
-Oh, are you so happy? -[Jeremiah] Yeah, so super.
-Oh, kamu bahagia sekali? -[Jeremiah] Ya, sangat bahagia.
-[Miles] Aw. -[Kiara] My little Tuskegee Airman!
-[Miles] Aduh. -[Kiara] Penerbang Tuskegee kecilku!
Sit down. Let's take it for a test spin.
Duduklah. Mari kita coba.
This is First Lieutenant Jeremiah Williams.
Ini Letnan Satu Jeremiah Williams.
[mimics radio crackling]
[meniru bunyi radio yang berderak]
Williams mission...
Misi Williams... [menirukan bunyi radio yang berderak]
...assignment, do you copy?
...tugas, apakah Anda mengerti?
[mimics radio crackling] I copy. This is air traffic control.
[meniru bunyi radio yang berderak] Saya mengerti. Ini kontrol lalu lintas udara.
And I have your first mission ready, First Lieutenant Jeremiah Williams.
Dan saya telah menyiapkan misi pertama Anda, Letnan Satu Jeremiah Williams.
Only if you choose to accept it. Do you choose to accept your mission?
Hanya jika Anda memilih untuk menerimanya. Apakah Anda memilih untuk menerima misi Anda?
Please let me know with a strong "copy." [mimics radio crackling]
Tolong beri tahu saya dengan "salinan" yang kuat. [meniru suara radio yang berderak]
May I... [mimics radio crackling] ...hear the mission first?
Bolehkah saya... [menirukan bunyi radio yang berderak] ...mendengar misinya terlebih dahulu?
Uh, yeah, yeah, your first mission is to have an amazing birthday.
Uh, ya, ya, misi pertamamu adalah merayakan ulang tahun yang mengagumkan.
Can you handle that mission? [mimics radio crackling]
Bisakah kamu menangani misi itu? [menirukan bunyi radio yang berderak]
Of course I can, air traffic control. Mission gladly accepted.
Tentu saja bisa, kontrol lalu lintas udara. Misi diterima dengan senang hati.
-Roger that. -[Kiara] But if you're gonna fly as fast
-Roger that. -[Kiara] Tapi jika kamu ingin terbang secepat itu
as a Bell P-39 Airacobra, you might need this.
sebagai Bell P-39 Airacobra, Anda mungkin memerlukan ini.
-Another one?! -[Kiara laughs]
-Satu lagi?! -[Kiara tertawa]
Oh, another one before it was time to open up the gifts?
Oh, satu lagi sebelum waktunya membuka hadiah?
[Kiara] Come on. Birthdays only come once a year.
[Kiara] Ayolah. Ulang tahun cuma datang setahun sekali.
[both laugh]
[keduanya tertawa]
-[shutter clicks] -[Jeremiah] Ooh, how does it look, Mama?
-[klik rana] -[Jeremiah] Ooh, bagaimana kelihatannya, Mama?
[Kiara] The most handsome little pilot I ever saw.
[Kiara] Pilot kecil tertampan yang pernah kulihat.
-[Jeremiah giggles] -[Kiara] Oh!
-[Jeremiah terkikik] -[Kiara] Oh!
What time is it? I gotta...
Jam berapa sekarang? Aku harus...
-[mouthing] It's time to go. -Oh, wait. Hold on.
-[berbisik] Waktunya pergi. -Oh, tunggu. Tunggu dulu.
[mimics radio crackling]
[meniru bunyi radio yang berderak]
-This is air traffic control. Go for me. -What's happening?
Ini kontrol lalu lintas udara. Ayo, aku antar. - Ada apa?
Oh, unfortunately, I have to make another pit stop.
Oh, sayangnya, saya harus berhenti sebentar lagi.
Gotta pick up a few things.
Harus mengambil beberapa hal.
But fly safe in my absence, please. Do you copy?
Tapi terbanglah dengan aman selama aku pergi, ya. Kau mengerti?
-[mimics radio crackling] -Good gracious!
-[menirukan bunyi radio yang berderak] -Astaga!
-[Miles chuckles] -Thank you for enjoying our party anyway.
-[Miles terkekeh] -Terima kasih sudah menikmati pesta kami.
[Miles] Fly safe. I'll be right back.
[Miles] Terbang dengan aman. Aku akan segera kembali.
Mwah.
Wow.
Okay, bye.
Oke, selamat tinggal.
Okay, Lieutenant, we gotta get you dressed.
Baiklah, Letnan, kita harus mendandanimu.
You gotta be fresh for your birthday!
Kamu harus segar untuk ulang tahunmu!
[Jeremiah] Oops, forgot Fren.
[Jeremiah] Ups, lupa Fren.
[♪ gentle music playing]
[♪ musik lembut dimainkan]
-[toy plane whirring] -[imitating airplane motor buzzing]
-[pesawat mainan berdengung] -[menirukan dengungan mesin pesawat]
-[toy plane clatters] -[giggling]
-[pesawat mainan berdenting] -[tertawa cekikikan]
Excuse me, First Lieutenant. No flying in the house.
Permisi, Letnan Satu. Dilarang terbang di dalam rumah.
-Aw, Mom, please? -I'm serious, baby. Mwah.
-Ah, Bu, kumohon? -Aku serius, sayang. Mwah.
Airmen only fly in the open sky.
Penerbang hanya terbang di langit terbuka.
[imitating airplane buzzing]
[meniru dengungan pesawat]
[phone vibrating]
[telepon bergetar]
-Hi, Sabrina. -[Sabrina] [on phone] Hi, Kiara.
-Hai, Sabrina. -[Sabrina] [di telepon] Hai, Kiara.
How's it going?
Apa kabar?
[Sabrina] Have you thought about your next book?
[Sabrina] Sudahkah kamu memikirkan buku berikutnya?
Oh, my God, yes! I--
Ya Tuhan, ya! Aku--
- [Sabrina] Really? -Absolutely.
- [Sabrina] Benarkah? - Tentu saja.
-[toy plane buzzing] -I... I have so many ideas
-[Pesawat mainan berdengung] -Aku... Aku punya banyak ide
about how to expand the world and the characters.
tentang cara memperluas dunia dan karakter.
[Sabrina] Great, because the publisher wants to put you on a book tour.
[Sabrina] Bagus, karena penerbit ingin mengajakmu tur buku.
Mommy, I almost did it!
Bu, aku hampir berhasil!
Jeremiah, I'm on a call. I said no flying in the house.
Jeremiah, aku sedang menelepon. Aku bilang jangan terbang di dalam rumah.
Go out front, and I'll watch you from the window, okay?
Pergilah ke depan, dan aku akan mengawasimu dari jendela, oke?
Okay.
Oke.
[Kiara] I love you.
[Kiara] Aku mencintaimu.
Yeah, sorry. He's just--
Ya, maaf. Dia hanya--
He's really excited about his gift.
Dia sungguh gembira dengan hadiahnya.
Ah, yes! Monday's great.
Ah, ya! Seninnya menyenangkan.
I would love that.
Saya sangat menyukai hal itu.
[toy motor buzzing]
[motor mainan berdengung]
[♪ tender music playing]
[♪ musik lembut dimainkan]
[Jeremiah] Flying over Benin.
[Yeremia] Terbang di atas Benin.
[toy plane whirring]
[pesawat mainan berdengung]
Ah! Oh, my God, Sabrina!
Ah! Ya Tuhan, Sabrina!
-The New York Times? -[Sabrina] Mm-hmm.
-The New York Times? -[Sabrina] Mm-hmm.
-They actually said that? -[Sabrina] Verbatim.
-Mereka benar-benar mengatakan itu? -[Sabrina] Kata demi kata.
-[toy plane buzzing] -Oh, my God. [chuckles]
-[pesawat mainan berdengung] -Ya Tuhan. [tertawa kecil]
Yes.
Ya.
[Sabrina] Okay, so let's set up a call.
[Sabrina] Oke, jadi mari kita atur panggilan.
-[alarm bleeping] -Yes. Absolutely.
-[alarm berbunyi] -Ya. Tentu saja.
Okay. When? Yeah.
Oke. Kapan? Ya.
This is First Lieutenant Jeremiah and Second Lieutenant Fren
Ini Letnan Satu Jeremiah dan Letnan Dua Fren
starting nosedive in T-minus three...
mulai menurun drastis pada T-minus tiga...
-[toy plane buzzing] -...two, one.
-[pesawat mainan berdengung] -...dua, satu.
Oh, no.
Oh, tidak.
-[♪ tender music fades out] -[alarm bleeping]
-[♪ musik lembut memudar] -[alarm berbunyi]
[Sabrina] Kiara, The New York Times is calling you "the voice of the future."
[Sabrina] Kiara, The New York Times memanggil Anda "suara masa depan."
Thank you so much for believing in me, Sabrina.
Terima kasih banyak telah mempercayaiku, Sabrina.
[water lapping]
[air menjilati]
Yeah, I'm gonna get back to cooking for this little man's party.
Ya, aku akan kembali memasak untuk pesta si kecil ini.
[Sabrina] Of course.
[Sabrina] Tentu saja.
Okay, talk soon.
Oke, sampai jumpa lagi.
[exhales]
[menghembuskan napas]
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
[grunting]
[dengkur]
[stool creaking]
[bangku berderit]
[wood creaking]
[kayu berderit]
Mission Control, Daddy is back with the goods!
Kontrol Misi, Ayah kembali dengan barangnya!
[door closes]
[pintu tertutup]
What's wrong?
Ada apa?
Sabrina just called and...
Sabrina baru saja menelepon dan...
said she just booked me a book tour!
katanya dia baru saja memesankan tur buku untukku!
-[laughing] -That's amazing!
-[tertawa] -Itu menakjubkan!
Well, let's get the party started, then.
Baiklah, mari kita mulai pestanya.
-Yes. -Where's J?
-Ya. -Dimana J?
He's out front.
Dia ada di depan.
No, he's not.
Tidak, dia bukan.
-You didn't see him? -No.
-Kamu tidak melihatnya? -Tidak.
[Kiara] Jeremiah!
[Kiara] Jeremiah!
[Miles] Buddy!
[Miles] Sobat!
[Kiara sighs]
[Kiara mendesah]
[softly] God!
[dengan lembut] Ya Tuhan!
He's not out there.
Dia tidak ada di luar sana.
[Kiara] Where is this boy?
[Kiara] Dimana anak laki-laki ini?
Probably hiding again. Jeremiah!
Mungkin bersembunyi lagi. Yeremia!
Jeremiah, come on. It's party time!
Jeremiah, ayo. Waktunya berpesta!
Jeremiah?
Yeremia?
[Miles] J!
[Miles] J!
If you want birthday cake, you gotta come out!
Jika kamu ingin kue ulang tahun, kamu harus keluar!
[Kiara] J?
[Kiara] J?
Okay, come out, baby. You know I don't like it when you do this.
Oke, keluarlah, sayang. Kau tahu aku tidak suka kalau kau melakukan ini.
Jeremiah!
Yeremia!
[Miles] J!
[Miles] J!
[distant rumbling]
[gemuruh dari kejauhan]
[water lapping]
[air menjilati]
-J! -[Kiara] No!
-J! -[Kiara] Tidak!
J!
J!
[water splashing]
[percikan air]
Oh! Oh! Oh, God! Come on, baby.
Oh! Oh! Oh, Tuhan! Ayo, sayang.
[Kiara sobbing]
[Kiara terisak]
-[Miles grunting] -[Kiara gasping]
-[Miles mendengus] -[Kiara terengah-engah]
Come on.
Ayo.
[grunting]
[dengkur]
Here, take him, take him.
Ini, bawa dia, bawa dia.
[Kiara] Come on, baby. No! No.
[Kiara] Ayolah, sayang. Tidak! Tidak.
Call 911!
Telepon 911!
Baby. Call 911!
Sayang. Telepon 911!
-No! [crying] -Is he breathing?
-Tidak! [menangis] -Apakah dia bernafas?
Yeah, so we just pulled my son out of the pool.
Ya, jadi kami baru saja menarik anak saya keluar dari kolam renang.
[sobbing and exhaling]
[menangis dan menghembuskan napas]
Ki, is he breathing yet? Keep pumping!
Ki, dia sudah bernapas? Terus pompa!
-Keep pumping his chest! -Oh, God!
-Terus pompa dadanya! -Ya Tuhan!
-[sobbing] -I need you to get here right now, please!
-[terisak] -Aku butuh kamu datang ke sini sekarang juga, kumohon!
J, can you hear me?
J, bisakah kamu mendengarku?
-Breathe, buddy. Breathe. -Come on, baby!
Bernapaslah, sobat. Bernapaslah. -Ayo, sayang!
[crying] It's not playtime anymore.
[menangis] Ini bukan waktunya bermain lagi.
Let me try. Jeremiah.
Biar aku coba, Yeremia.
It's okay. No, it's okay.
Tidak apa-apa. Tidak apa-apa.
-Okay... -[Miles grunting]
-Oke... -[Miles mendengus]
What do I do? What did I do?
Apa yang harus kulakukan? Apa yang telah kulakukan?
Somebody help us!
Seseorang tolong kami!
[sobbing] Oh, no!
[terisak] Oh, tidak!
J! Breathe!
J! Bernapaslah!
[Kiara wailing]
[Kiara meratap]
Come on, breathe, buddy. Breathe!
Ayo, bernapaslah, sobat. Bernapaslah!
[panting] J!
[terengah-engah] J!
[screaming] No! No!
[berteriak] Tidak! Tidak!
No, no, no!
Tidak tidak tidak!
[sobbing] No!
[terisak] Tidak!
[panting and grunting]
[terengah-engah dan mendengus]
We can't wait. We can't wait.
Kami tak sabar. Kami tak sabar.
Come on, we can't wait. Let's go!
Ayo, kita tidak sabar. Ayo berangkat!
Let's go. Let's go.
Ayo pergi. Ayo pergi.
[♪ somber music playing]
[♪ musik sedih dimainkan]
[softly] It's all my fault.
[dengan lembut] Ini semua salahku.
[Miles] Don't say that.
[Miles] Jangan katakan itu.
I stopped watching him for 60 seconds...
Saya berhenti menontonnya selama 60 detik...
and he was gone.
dan dia pun pergi.
I'll never hear him say,
Aku tidak akan pernah mendengar dia berkata,
"I love you, Mommy."
"Aku mencintaimu, Ibu."
I'll never kiss his forehead again.
Aku tidak akan pernah mencium keningnya lagi.
[crying] I'll never kiss his cheek.
[menangis] Aku tidak akan pernah mencium pipinya.
[Kiara sniffles]
[Kiara terisak]
I'm not a mother anymore. [exhales]
Aku bukan seorang ibu lagi. [menghela napas]
You'll always be his mother.
Kamu akan selalu menjadi ibunya.
Just like I'll always be his father, no matter what.
Sama seperti aku akan selalu menjadi ayahnya, apa pun yang terjadi.
[breathing shakily]
[bernapas gemetar]
I couldn't bring myself to say this to anybody...
Aku tak sanggup mengatakan hal ini pada siapa pun...
but after the accident, I, um...
tetapi setelah kecelakaan itu, saya, um...
[clears throat]
[berdeham]
...I kept having this dream
...aku terus menerus bermimpi ini
about Jeremiah and, um...
tentang Yeremia dan, um...
In the dream, he was in the pool.
Dalam mimpinya, dia berada di kolam renang.
But he was, like... he was happy.
Tapi dia seperti... dia bahagia.
He was laughing, he was smiling. He was all...
Dia tertawa, dia tersenyum. Dia...
He was asking me all kind of random questions,
Dia menanyakan berbagai pertanyaan acak kepadaku,
insisting I call him First Lieutenant.
memaksaku memanggilnya Letnan Satu.
[softly] He's so beautiful in the dream.
[dengan lembut] Dia begitu tampan dalam mimpi.
He's perfect in the dream. Perfect.
Dia sempurna dalam mimpi. Sempurna.
[normal] And then I'd, um...
[normal] Dan kemudian saya, um...
I wake up and I'm in cold sweats.
Aku terbangun dan berkeringat dingin.
So, it just got to the point where, like...
Jadi, hal itu sampai pada titik di mana, seperti...
[exhales sharply]
[menghembuskan napas tajam]
...I was scared to go to sleep
...aku takut untuk tidur
because...
Karena...
I'd wake up and he'd still be...
Aku terbangun dan dia masih...
So, it was almost worse, like seeing him all the time,
Jadi, itu hampir lebih buruk, seperti melihatnya sepanjang waktu,
and then waking up, and he's not...
dan kemudian terbangun, dan dia tidak...
He's not...
Dia tidak...
[inhales deeply]
[menarik napas dalam-dalam]
[exhales] But then...
[menghembuskan napas] Tapi kemudian...
I was losing you at the same time.
Aku kehilanganmu pada saat yang sama.
So, when you called me a coward, you were right.
Jadi, saat Anda menyebut saya pengecut, Anda benar.
Because...
Karena...
I was scared that I was gonna break.
Saya takut saya akan hancur.
And just...
Dan hanya...
I didn't know how to handle it.
Saya tidak tahu bagaimana menanganinya.
I didn't know what to do, so I said I was moving forward.
Saya tidak tahu harus berbuat apa, jadi saya katakan saya akan terus maju.
But really, I was just scared.
Tapi sebenarnya, saya hanya takut.
[breathing shakily]
[bernapas gemetar]
I didn't know you were hurting so much.
Aku tidak tahu kamu terluka sedalam ini.
I was so wrapped up in my own pain.
Aku begitu terjerumus dalam rasa sakitku sendiri.
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
[sighs] I'm so tired.
[menghela napas] Aku sangat lelah.
I'm so tired, Miles.
Aku sangat lelah, Miles.
[sniffles]
[mengendus]
[sighs] I know you are, too.
[menghela napas] Aku tahu kau juga begitu.
I'm exhausted, Ki.
Aku lelah, Ki.
[snorts]
[mendengus]
Absolutely exhausted.
Benar-benar kelelahan.
You're the smart one, but I know we gotta find a way to get past this.
Kamu memang pintar, tapi aku tahu kita harus menemukan cara untuk melewati ini.
We gotta forgive ourselves for all of it.
Kita harus memaafkan diri kita sendiri atas semua itu.
[Entity buzzing]
[Entitas berdengung]
[buzzing intensifies]
[dengungan semakin kuat]
[♪ ethereal music playing]
[♪ musik halus dimainkan]
[gasps]
[terkesiap]
Hi, Mommy.
Hai, Ibu.
[Kiara gasping]
[Kiara terengah-engah]
Don't cry. Don't be sad.
Jangan menangis. Jangan bersedih.
[laughing] I'm not sad, baby.
[tertawa] Aku tidak sedih, sayang.
I'm not sad. I'm so happy to see you.
Aku tidak sedih. Aku sangat senang melihatmu.
Hi, Daddy.
Hai, Ayah.
I can't believe you're here.
Aku tak percaya kau ada di sini.
[Kiara sighs]
[Kiara mendesah]
[Jeremiah] I'm always here with you.
[Yeremia] Aku selalu di sini bersamamu.
I wanted to help you and Daddy stay together.
Aku ingin membantumu dan Ayah tetap bersama.
[laughs and sniffles]
[tertawa dan terisak]
It was you the whole time?
Itu kamu selama ini?
[Jeremiah] I had to fix the chain that connects us.
[Jeremiah] Saya harus memperbaiki rantai yang menghubungkan kita.
I get to fly whenever I want now.
Sekarang saya bisa terbang kapan pun saya mau.
[sighs] I miss you so much.
[menghela napas] Aku sangat merindukanmu.
[sniffles] I love you.
[mengendus] Aku cinta kamu.
[♪ gentle dramatic music playing]
[♪ musik dramatis yang lembut dimainkan]
[Kiara's lips smack]
[Bibir Kiara berdecak]
I'm so sorry.
Saya turut berduka cita.
It's okay. It's not your fault.
Tidak apa-apa. Itu bukan salahmu.
[♪ dramatic music intensifies]
[♪ musik dramatis semakin intens]
[Kiara sighs]
[Kiara mendesah]
[chuckles] Thank you.
[tertawa kecil] Terima kasih.
Fly with the ancestors, baby.
Terbang bersama leluhur, sayang.
First Lieutenant Jeremiah Williams.
Letnan Satu Jeremiah Williams.
You have done a phenomenal job with your mission.
Anda telah melakukan pekerjaan fenomenal dengan misi Anda.
[sniffles]
[mengendus]
You did it.
Kamu berhasil.
[voice breaking] It was you.
[suara terputus-putus] Itu kamu.
[♪ melancholic music playing]
[♪ musik melankolis dimainkan]
My moon.
Bulan saya.
My North Star.
Bintang Utara saya.
[Kiara sighs]
[Kiara mendesah]
[♪ music stops]
[♪ musik berhenti]
[birds chirping]
[kicauan burung]
[record player clicking]
[suara pemutar rekaman berbunyi]
[vinyl popping]
[vinil bermunculan]
[♪ smooth jazz music playing on record player]
[♪ Musik jazz lembut diputar di pemutar rekaman]
[sighs]
[menghela napas]
[sighs deeply]
[menghela napas dalam-dalam]
[♪ smooth jazz music continues]
[♪ musik jazz lembut berlanjut]
[♪ music fades out]
[♪ musik memudar]